All of your body language is important,
but in this video, we're going to concentrate on the face.
In 2014, the University of Glasgow concluded
that there are 42 muscles in the human face.
That's 42 opportunities you have to help convey your message.
Unfortunately, not everyone activates all the muscles
in their face, and the result of that
is that your message can end up falling a little flat.
Here's a comparison to show you what I mean.
There's a big storm coming in this Friday,
which will definitely impact your weekend plans,
but the forecast next week is looking clear for holiday travel.
There's a big storm coming in this weekend,
which will definitely impact your holiday plans,
but the forecast next week is looking clear for holiday travel.
Now, in both examples, the energy in my voice was similar.
However, you'll notice that in the second example,
I was really using a lot more of my facial muscles.
In addition, I was also smiling more.
Smiling is a great way to instantly add energy to your face.
Now, with the weather forecast,
we're not always smiling about what we have to talk about,
but when you do have the opportunity,
don't forget to use your smile.
Now, if you need help, activating the muscles in your face.
Here's a simple exercise that actors often use.
It's called lemon face, lion face.
And all you do is contort your face
so that you act like you just bit into a very sour lemon
and then quickly transform your face into a roaring lion.
It goes a little something like this.
Repeat that a few times.
Yes, it seems a little goofy,
but it's a great way to warm up those facial muscles.